Ethan McDowell

Web Developer

Address Detroit, MI, 48209

Phone (313) 400-5611

E-mail ethan.r.mcdowell@gmail.com

Ambitious web developer brings enthusiasm and detailed understanding of various programming languages to webpage planning, development and maintenance. Experience designing and developing sites from concept to roll out. Foundational grasp of various CSS, HTML, and JavaScript options, plugins, development platforms and security requirements according to up-to-date standards.

Skills

HTML	
CSS	
JavaScript	
JQuery	
Node.js	

Work History

2018-08 - Current

Web Developer

Street Beet, Detroit, MI

- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Collaborated with restaurant owners to determine organizational need, designing pages to meet demand.

2017-08 - Current

Bartender

Checker Bar, Detroit, MI

- Took customer orders and capitalized on opportunities to sell special beverage and food options.
- Managed accurate register and produced daily sales reports backing up inventory usage numbers.
- Managed bar inventory, restocked supplies and placed orders for spirits, beer, wines and mixers.

2011-10 - 2017-07

Practice Manager

Mohawk Village Medical, New York, NY

- Assessed processes and procedures, complying with OSHA and HIPAA regulations.
- Supported duties for diagnostic and technical treatment procedures, such as setting up and operating special medical equipment and apparatus.
- Developed and maintained electronic record management systems to analyze and process data.
- Collected blood samples using vacutainer tubes, tourniquets, syringes, butterfly needles, and straight needles.

Education

2020-09 - Current

Certification: Full-Stack Web Development

Michigan State University - Detroit, MI

2006-01 - 2010-05

Bachelor of Science: Medical Laboratory Management

University Of New Hampshire - Durham, NH

Projects

askKaren: https://emkaygru.github.io/AskKaren/

Restaurant search application with an interesting twist. Used Zomato and BadAdvice APIs.

My Weather Dashboard: https://ethanrmcdowell.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/ Searchable weather dashboard utilizing the OpenWeather API.

Work Day Scheduler: https://ethanrmcdowell.github.io/Work-Scheduler/ Uses JavaScript, moment.js, and specific CSS classes to provide an up to date daily schedule.